Lisbon啊...
Lisbon...
都结束了 完结了
It's over. It's done.
我只是给你报个平安
I just want you to know I'm okay.
我会想念你的
And I'm gonna miss you.
两年后
那就是警察的职责
And that's what police do.
我们帮助遇到麻烦的人
We help people that are in trouble,
阻止惹是生非的人
and we stop people from making trouble.
有时很辛苦
It's a hard job sometimes,
但我认为这是世界上最好的工作
but I think it's the best job there is.
你们呢? 有没有人想
What about you? Does anybody want to be
长大以后做警察呀?
a police officer when they grow up?
你们还有时间考虑一下
Well, there's time to think about it.
有问题吗?
Any questions?
有 有 有!
Ooh, ooh, ooh! Ooh! Ooh, ooh!
你开枪打过人吗?
Did you ever shoot somebody?
嗯 确实有
Well, actually, yes.
他们有死掉吗?
Did they die?
重点是 世界上有坏人
Point is, there are bad people in the world.
不是全部 但却有
Not all, but some.
有时候你不得不做一些
And sometimes you have to do things
你不想做的事
you don't want to do
来确保避免更糟糕的事情发生
to make sure worse things don't happen.
- 是不是流了很多血呀?  - 我想今天的时间差不多了
- Was there lots of blood?  - I'm afraid that's all the time we have.
- 我们要说什么呀?  - 谢谢 Lisbon警长!
- What do we say?  - Thank you, Chief Lisbon!
嘿 Henry 怎么了?
Hey, Henry, what's up?
外面有个人想找你
There's a man here wants to speak with you.
一个叫Abbott的探员
An Agent Abbott,
呃 是联邦调查局的
uh, with the FBI.
- Abbott探员?  - 他自己这样说的
- Abbott?  - That's what he said.
- 让他进来  - 好的
- Send him in.  - Okay.
什么事?
Yes?
你确定要让他现在进来吗?
Do you want me to send him in now?
对
Yes.
嗨 Lisbon
Hi, Lisbon.
嗯
Hmm.
你的... 办公室不错
Well, you... have a nice place.
对吧?
Hmm?
你在这多久 18个月了吧?
You've been here, what, 18 months?
有Jane的消息吗?
Have you heard from Jane?
没有
Nope.
一点消息都没? 没有邮件 没有电话?
Nothing? No e-mail, no phone call?
没有
No.
嗯
Hmm.
Rigsby或者Van Pelt呢?
What about Rigsby or Van Pelt?
他们有没有收到消息?
Have they heard anything?
我今晚就会和他们一起吃晚饭
I'm having dinner with them tonight.
要不你加入我们吧? 你可以亲自问他们
Why don't you join us? You could ask them yourself.
嗯... 那Cho呢?
Mm... Hmm. And Cho?
我很长时间没收到他的消息了
Haven't heard from him in ages.
我不知道Jane在哪 坦白说 我也不在乎
I don't know where Jane is, and frankly, I don't care.
是吗? 呃...
No? Well...
你俩以前那么亲密
you two were so close.
那是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
哦
Hmm.
你们打算什么时候才放弃追捕他?
When are you guys gonna give up chasing him?
我们可是联邦调查局 不会轻言放弃
Oh, we're the F.B.I. We don't give up.
嗯
Hmm.
贝壳真漂亮
That is a nice shell.
是玛瑙贝
It's a cowrie.
哦
Oh.
可以看下吗?
May I?
随便
Sure.
有人说贝壳会一直带着
You know, they say a shell always carries around
海浪的声音
the sound of the ocean with it.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：伊娃 失眠影 捞小盐
校对：失眠影
超感神探 第六季第9集
亲爱的Lisbon
Dear Lisbon,
希望你一切安好
I hope this finds you well.
这里一切都好
All's well here.
我每天过得很有规律
I have my routines.
天气终于有点转凉了
Weather's finally turned a little cooler.
但一点都不冷
Far from cold.
海边还是很温暖
And the ocean is still warm
温暖到招来了
and with the warmer incurrence
一大群海洋生物
comes in a bundle of sea lives.
就在昨天我看到一群海豚
Yesterday I saw a pod of dolphins play
在岸边很近的地方嬉戏...
so close to the shore...
近到我快可以摸到它们了
I could almost touch them.
我想你也会喜欢这些的
That is the kind of things I think you could enjoy.
女士们 早上好
Jane先生 早上好
早上好 早上好
今天怎样呀? Jane先生
很好 谢谢
请给我点时间
今天的邮费多少钱?
今天?
75分
难以置信啊
Unbelievable.
比昨天便宜 但比上周贵
Cheaper than yesterday, but more expensive than last week.
好... 谢谢
不客气
有人找过我吗?
没有 没有 从来没有
好吧
祝你们今天愉快 女士们
也祝你愉快!
一直问有没有人找他 真可怜
一直那么帅
对 很帅
一直那么有礼貌
对 很有礼貌
但他的西班牙语太烂了!
没有比他更烂的了
喂 Patrick! Patrick!
Patrick! Patrick!
用硬币变魔术给我们看吧!
真要来吗 小伙子们?
Oh, really, guys?
我不会变其它魔术了
求求你啦!
很执着 我只能说 非常执着
Very persistent, I must say. Very persistent.
好吧
但只变一次
只变一次
好吧? 看看这是什么?
Huh? What have we got here?
对 是硬币
Yeah.
去哪儿了?
去哪儿了呢?
Donde esta?
喂!
Hey!
你个小杂种走路长点眼睛
去!
Uhh!
喂!
Hey!
你看什么看?
What are you looking at?
没有
Nothing.
早上好 Victor
Buenas dias, Victor.
Jane先生 早上好
Ah, senor Jane. Buenas dias.
很抱歉
你的衬衫还没好 很遗憾
但我下午一定做好
没关系 我可以再来的
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
我们有个问题
什么问题呢?
你的衬衫一定要有"肩章"
抱歉 一定要有
Cha... Charre... 肩章?
Cha... Charre... Charreteras?
是什么... 呃...
What... Uh...
是Charreteras 明白吗?
Charreteras. Charreteras. Charreteras. Si?
- 就是这个 明白吗?  - 哦 是肩章
- Come estas. Si?  - Ah. Epaulettes.
- 对! 对!  - 肩章
- Si! Si!  - Charreteras.
对 它们很精致 很有男子气概
是吧? 是吧?
Si? Si?
我觉得不用了
我不会多收你钱的!
不用了 谢谢
太好了
很明显...
时尚
是无法教的!
干活去!
嘿 Hugo
Hey, Hugo.
你好吗?
How you doing?
Alfredo啊...
Alfredo...
你今天怎样?
我猜下
你要炒鸡蛋和奶茶
太感谢你了
你尝下咖啡会死吗?
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
你是美国人吗?
From the U.S.?
我无可挑剔的西班牙语没有骗到你吗?
You weren't fooled by my impeccable Spanish?
没有 不管怎样...
No. Anyway...
你在看书呢 抱歉
You're reading. Sorry.
问题是 呃 我怀念讲英语
Thing is, uh, I miss speaking english.
Roger是这里唯一一个说英语的人
Roger's the only other English speaker,
但他... 他不太爱讲话
And he's... well, he's not a great talker.
事实证明受人理解是一件无人珍视的美事
Turns out being understood is an underrated pleasure.
我懂的
I can imagine. Mm.
我不打扰你了
I'll leave you alone.
没关系
No problem.
貌似你快看完了
Looks like you're nearly finished.
我看完之后你想看吗?
Do you want it when I'm finished?
我很乐意
I wouldn't mind it.
在这很难找到英文书
It's not easy to get books in English around here.
好啊
Okay.
书好看吗?
Is it any good?
你喜欢神秘谋杀案吗?
You like murder mysteries?
不太喜欢
Not really.
那你可能不喜欢这本书了
Then you probably won't like it.
无论怎样我都会看的
Well, I'll take it anyway.
饥不择食 对吧?
Beggars can't be choosers, can they?
对 没得选
No, they can't.
你要过来和我一起吗?
Do you want to join me?
好啊
Sure.
我叫Patrick
Patrick.
- 我叫Kim  - 嗨
- Kim.  - Hi.
你来自东南岸吧?
So you're from the, uh, southeast?
弗吉尼亚州?
Virginia?
耳朵真灵 猜对了
Good ear. Yeah.
你呢?
You?
呃 我... 我到处跑 现在住在这
Well, I... I lived all over. Right now I live here.
我之前在这个岛的另一边
I was on the other side of the island,
不过人们告诉我这边的沙滩好多了
but people told me the beaches on this side were better.
- 确实如此  - 你和妻子一起来的吗?
- That's true.  - You here with your wife?
不 只有我
No, just me.
对 不 我妻子 呃...
Oh, yeah, no. My wife, uh...
呃... 我不再是已婚了
Uh... not married anymore.
你呢?
You?
我? 没结婚
Me? No.
很好
Great.
我是说 如果... 如果你喜欢不结婚 保持单身...
I mean, it's great if you... if you like not being married...
就挺好的
being single.
- 的确很享受  - 很好
- I do.  - Great.
- 非常感谢  - 不客气
- Ah, muchas gracias.  - Si. De nada.
我来这儿是逃避的 思考些事情
I came here to get away, think about things.
你在思考什么?
What are you thinking about?
最近工作上有个升职的机会
I've been offered a promotion at work,
但我不确定想不想要
but I'm not sure I want it.
为什么犹豫?
Why is that?
哦... 更多工作
Oh... It's more work.
更多烦恼
It's more hassle.
虽然有更多钱 但值得吗?
Eh, more money, but is it worth it?
看来你问自己的这个问题
Well, sounds like you're asking yourself
是问对了
the right questions.
住这里有点奇怪
Must be strange to live here.
太漂亮了...
It's so beautiful. I...
如果一直待在这儿
I think if I were here full-time,
我会觉得自己
I'd feel like I was living
住在梦境里 你明白吗?
in some kind of dream world, you know?
有时候的确如此
Ah, sometimes it's like that.
梦境没什么不好的 对吧?
There's nothing wrong with dream worlds, right?
你就是长住的
You're here to stay.
也许吧
Maybe.
真是个神秘的男人
Man of mystery.
真的?
Really?
我可没想故作神秘
I don't mean to be mysterious.
我妻子死了
My wife died.
发生了一些事 我做了些事...
Some things happened, I did some things, and...
我暂时还不是很想谈这些
I don't really know how to talk about it yet.
我猜这就是我还戴着戒指的原因
I guess that's why I still wear the ring.
我只是... 还没准备好
I'm just... not ready.
我想我明白
I think I understand.
这就是我来这儿的原因
Anyway, that's why I'm here.
这地方可真不赖
It's not a bad place to be.
对吧? 这儿很漂亮
Right? It's beautiful.
是个天堂
It's paradise.
正是如此
Exactly.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
你说英语吗?
Do you speak English?
是的 先生 很流利
Yes, sir. I speak very good, sir.
很好 你叫什么?
Ah. Good. What's your name?
Morales 先生 我叫Franklin Morales
Morales. Franklin Morales, sir.
Morales 对吧?
Morales, huh?
你见过这个人吗?
Have you seen this guy?
没见过 先生
No, sir.
那好
Okay then.
如果你见到他了...
If you see him...
- 就告诉我 好吗?  - 好的 先生
- you'll tell me, yes?  - Yes, sir.
好的
All right.
非常感谢
Muchas gracias.
好了 伙计们 我们安顿一下
All right, fellas, let's get settled,
就去吃东西
then we'll go get something to eat.
嘿 Roger 你怎么样?
Hey, Roger, what's up?
谢谢
Gracias.
- Roger 这位是Kim 他是Roger  - 你好
- Roger, Kim. Kim, Roger.  - Hi.
见到你真是... 感动得热泪盈眶
My eyes were... fluid cobras.
是呀 很高兴见到你
Yeah. Good to see you.
他来了多久了?
How long has he been here?
不知道 挺长时间了
Uh, not sure. Long time.
看得出来
You can tell.
稍等
Un momento.
嘿 Jane
Jane.
是找你的
失陪一下
Oh. Uh, excuse me.
喂?
Hello?
- 我是Franklin  - 嘿 Franklin 怎么了?
- It's Franklin.  - Hey, Franklin. What's up?
有三个美国警察来了酒店
Three big American police checked in.
在找你呢
Looking for you.
他们已经在这儿了?
They're there now?
没错
Yes.
好吧 看看你还能打探到什么消息
Okay, well, see what else you can find out.
我会再联系你的 好吗?
I'll be in touch, okay?
当然 没问题
Yes, of course.
再见
Bye.
没事吧?
Is everything all right?
没事 只是...
Uh, yeah. Fine. Uh, just some...
有些人想要见我
some people who want to meet with me.
听着 我得回市区了
Listen, I have to head back up to town.
你想和我一起回去吗?
Do you want to come with me?
当然
Sure.
回头见
See you around.
- 一定  - 再见
- I'm sure I will.  - Bye.
站直
真漂亮
非常漂亮
加上肩章肯定更好看
你还真是固执己见
- 衬衫真好看  - 谢谢
- That's a nice shirt.  - Thanks.
去换衣服吧
和你聊得很愉快
Well, this was nice.
我知道你还有人要见
I know you have people to see.
很不幸 的确是这样
Yes, uh, unfortunately, I do, yeah.
没问题 但我在想...
No problem. Hey, um, but I was wondering...
你知道附近有哪家不错的餐厅能吃晚餐吗?
do you, uh, know a good place around here for dinner?
你在邀请我共进晚餐吗?
Are you asking me out for dinner?
是的
Yeah.
我想你知道当地人会去的好地方
I figure you'll know a good place where the locals go.
没错 我的确知道...
Yeah, uh, I do. Um...
我... 知道...
Yes, I do... know...
我们要不约了在这儿碰面...
Well, why don't we meet here at, uh...
就... 八点吧?
oh, I don't know... 8:00?
- 说定了  - 好
- Deal.  - Okay.
八点
8:00.
一会儿见
See ya then.
在找你的人叫Abbott
The man who asks about you is Abbott.
入住资料上登记的就是这个名字
That is the name on the register.
他现在在哪儿?
Hmm. Where is he now?
他在吃饭 本来还有两个人跟他在一起
Eating. The other two men are with him,
- 但他们走了  - 谢谢
- but they leave.  - Ahh. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
那家伙是谁?
Who's that guy?
他叫Danny Otero
Danny Otero.
卖毒品的
Sells drugs.
来这儿从越南人手上买海洛因的
Comes here to buy heroin from Vietnamese.
人不怎么样
Bad business.
英语怎么说? 呃... 给小费很抠门
How you say? Um... lousy tipper.
给小费很抠门
Lousy tipper.
对 没错
Yeah. Yeah.
很抠门
Lousy tipper.
嘿 Abbott
Abbott.
你怎么样?
How the heck are you?
我还以为我们得翻遍岛上每一寸土地
And here we thought we were gonna have to turn over
才能找到你呢
every rock on this island to find you.
我听说你来了
I heard you were here.
觉得礼貌起见 应该过来打声招呼
Well, it's only polite to stop by and say hi.
旅途如何?
Oh, how was the flight?
太颠簸了
Bumpy.
你这样直接来见面还真是自信
Pretty confident of you to front up like this.
我有引渡法护身
The extradition laws are on my side.
我知道你没法抓我
I know you can't touch me.
谁说我想抓你的?
Who said I wanted to touch you?
- 我是来和你谈条件的  - 这样
- I'm here to make you an offer.  - Oh.
管事的人认为
The powers-that-be
你对联邦调查局的价值很大
decided that you could be valuable to the FBI.
如果你愿意来为我们工作 联邦调查局很愿意
The Bureau is willing to drop all the charges against you
撤销对你的一切指控
if you come and work for us.
为联邦调查局工作?
For the FBI?
没错
That's right.
这是条款
There are the terms.
要知道 我想说清楚
You know, I want to be very clear.
我不喜欢这个交易
I don't like this deal.
如果要我说 就该给你脑袋套上麻袋
If it were up to me, you would be headed home
用货运机运回美国
in a cargo plane with a sack over your head.
但我也只是来传话的
But, hey, I'm just the messenger.
很诱人的提议 但我不信
Interesting proposition. I'm not buying it.
不信?
No?
无论我是什么态度...
Whatever my feelings are about it...
这条件很不错了 Jane
this is a good deal, Jane.
你真的应该考虑一下
You really need to consider it.
我已经过腻那种生活了
I am done with that life.
我做了该做的事
I did what I had to do,
也已经放下了过去
and I've moved on.
那种生活是一份你干得很好的工作
That life was a job that you were very good at.
如果你回来 可以帮助很多人
If you come back, you can help a lot of people.
你有天赋
You have a gift.
那不是天赋
It's not a gift.
无论如何 这会让你离开这座岛
Whatever it is, it'll get you off this island,
然后重新开始生活
and you can start your life again.
我已经做到了 谢谢
I have. Thank you.
好吧
Okay.
我们还会在这儿待一天 如果你改主意了就来找我
We'll be here for another day if you change your mind.
你怎么找到我的?
How'd you find me?
你给你女朋友Lisbon写的信
The letters to your girlfriend Lisbon.
要知道 你先把信寄给马戏团的朋友
You know, it was pretty smart
再让他们偷偷带给Lisbon
to send them to your carny friends
这招挺聪明的
and have them sneak them over to her.
但还不够聪明
Just not quite smart enough.
我终于黑进了防火墙
So I finally managed to hack through the firewall,
结果发现偷取信用卡号码的
and it turns out the cyber mastermind
黑客高手竟然是一个明尼阿波利斯的11岁孩子
stealing credit card numbers is an 11-year-old from Minneapolis.
什么?
What?
没错 他把信息卖给朋友
Yeah. He was selling them to his friends
他们都用来买限量版球鞋了
so they could buy limited-edition sneakers.
- 他被捕了吗?  - 我不知道
- Did he get arrested?  - I don't know.
我们把信息给了明尼阿波利斯警局
We turned the information over to the Minneapolis P.D.
事实上他们抓到了 我查过
Actually, they did. I checked.
他会被当成少年犯来审判
And he's gonna be tried as a juvenile.
就是这样
Oh, well, there you go.
所以电子监控公司的生意不错吧?
So the digital surveillance company is going well, huh?
不错 我们已经开张
Yeah. We've been up and running now
大概15个月了...
for, uh, 15 months, and...
不管你信不信 收入非常稳定
already turning a tidy profit, believe it or not.
是很不错
Yeah. Nice.
你过得如何?
How are things here?
还是老样子 大多数都是酒后偷车的案子...
Same. You know, it's mostly D.U.I.s, stolen bikes...
但我挺喜欢的
but I like it that way.
很安静祥和
It's nice and quiet.
是保姆打来的 抱歉 喂?
It's the babysitter. Excuse me. Hello?
Maddy有点低烧
Maddy's got a slight fever.
Grace很担心 我告诉她没事的
Grace worries. I try and tell her it's nothing,
- 但终归是第一个孩子 还是担心  - 我明白
- but first baby, you know?  - Sure.
- 我能问你件事吗 Wayne?  - 问吧
- Can I ask you something, Wayne?  - Mm.
- 你想念加州调查局吗?  - 恩
- Do you ever miss the CBI?  - Hmm.
当然 有时候会想
Sure. Sometimes.
我是说 我和Grace都很忙
I mean, Grace and I are so busy,
真的没有太多时间去想这些
I don't really have much time to think about it.
事情太忙了
Things are so hectic.
我原来挺想念的 但现在不了
I used to miss it, but not anymore.
这里挺好的
Yeah. Everything here's good.
要知道... 就是挺好的
You know, it's just... it's good.
那很好 头儿
That's great, boss.
我不是你们的头儿了
I am not your boss anymore.
她说孩子烧到39度了
She says her fever's up to 102.7.
抱歉 我们得走了
Oh. I'm sorry. We're out of here.
- 真对不起  - 没事的
- I'm so sorry.  - No, it's fine.
我送你们上车
But I'll walk you to your car.
所以... 说到那些想和你见面的人
So... those people that wanted to meet with you,
你后来和他们见面了吗?
did you meet with them?
见了
Yeah.
谈得如何?
How'd it go?
呃 挺有意思的
Uh, it was interesting.
他们给我找了份工作
They made me a job offer.
嗯?
Hmm?
简单地说 要是我同意为他们工作
Basically, if I go and work for them,
我就可以回到美国
then I can go back to the U.S.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
其实未必
Not really.
我已经差不多放下过去了
I've kind of moved on.
回去就相当于重蹈覆辙
It would be going backwards.
我觉得那样不太好
And I don't think that's healthy.
那你... 到底是做什么的呢?
What is it that you... do, anyway?
- 我是做什么的?  - 没错
- What do I do?   - Yeah.
嗯
Hmm.
我... 我负责找人
I, uh... I look for people.
听起来很有趣
Sounds intriguing.
的确 过去是的
It is. Was.
过去觉得有趣
It was fun.
可归根结底你还是得回家啊
Still, you get to go home.
难道没有什么值得你留恋吗?
Aren't there things that you miss?
有 当然有
Sure, of course.
谢谢你
Thank you for this.
我需要陪伴
I needed the company.
我之前自认为不需要 但...
I didn't think I did, but, uh...
结果... 看来我还是需要的
Ah, it turns out that... I do.
谁不需要陪伴呢?
Who doesn't?
想去跳支舞吗?
You want to go dancing?
好啊
Yeah.
夜色真美
It's a beautiful night.
的确
It is.
我觉得好像有人在跟踪我们
I feel like somebody's following us.
- 我去跟他们谈谈  - 别!
- I'll just go and talk to them.  - No!
- Patrick 别去  - 没关系的 我西语说得很溜的
- Patrick, come on.  - No, it's fine. I speak the lingo.
你干嘛要...
Why don't you...
嘿 伙计 出来吧
Hey, guys, come over so I can see you.
天啊
Oh, my god.
你个小杂种走路长点眼睛
少多管闲事!
Patrick 没事吧?
Patrick?
感觉真棒
That feels good.
你真好闻
You smell nice.
你该去看医生
You should see a doctor.
不... 不
No... no.
你可能得了脑震荡
You could have a concussion.
不 我只是... 需要休息
Nah, I just... just need to rest.
我昨晚喝得很醉
I was very, uh, drunk last night.
没错
Yes.
发生什么了?
What happened?
你被人打了 拿着
You got beat up. Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
太好喝了
Oh, that is so good.
你感觉怎么样了?
How are you feeling?
喝了这个好多了
Better now, after this.
你茶泡得真好
You make good tea.
谢谢
Thank you.
我今早收到一条短信
I got a text this morning.
是工作的事 我今天就得赶回去
My work. I have to go back today.
我中午要赶飞机 我还要打包 而且...
I have a midday flight, and I have to pack, and...
我理解 你得回去了
Yeah, I understand. You got to go back.
是啊 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
不 没... 没关系的
Oh, no, it's... it's fine.
一切都多谢了
Thanks for everything.
哦...
Oh...
跟你在一起这段时间真的很开心 Patrick
I really had a wonderful time with you, Patrick.
嗯
Mm.
再见...
Anyway...
Hugo啊!
Hugo!
Alfredo呢?
Alfredo?
怎么回事?
What happened?
Otero来过
他喝得烂醉
这狗叫个不停
砰
Pow.
你打算怎么办?
没什么可办的
你又能怎么办呢?
等我这儿忙完了...
就给你煎些蛋去
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
我就觉得在这能找到你
I was hoping I'd find you here.
我想给你一样东西
I wanted to give you something.
太谢谢了
Oh, thank you.
不 是该我谢你... 跟我共进晚餐什么的
No, thank you... for dinner and everything.
- 我...  - 你说得对
- I...  - You're right.
受人理解是一件无人珍视的美事
Being understood is an underrated pleasure.
我把我家里电话留给你...
Let me give you my home phone number...
说不定哪天你就回国了
in case you ever make it back to the States.
世事难料嘛
You never know.
你可能会想打给我
You might wanna give me a call.
有可能吧
I might.
再见了 Patrick
Goodbye, Patrick.
希望你的决定为你带来好运
Good luck with your decision.
还有件事...
You know, one thing...
回去未必意味着回到过去
going back doesn't have to mean going backwards.
回去照样可以放下过去
It can mean moving on.
我是Abbott
Abbott.
嘿 探员
Hey, G-man.
我准备好回家了
I'm ready to come home.
哇 真是好消息
Wow. That is good news.
但是要按我的条款来 明白吗?
But on my terms. Is that clear?
我一回美国
And when we get back to the U.S.,
就要和管事的人见面
I want a meeting with whatever powers-that-be
明确这些是正式条款
to make clear that those are the terms.
我肯定我们可以做到
I'm sure we can work out something like that.
- 我要Lisbon也在场  - 为什么?
- And I want Lisbon there.  - Why?
要是Lisbon不在 我就不答应
Lisbon's there, or I don't do it.
而且如果你嘴上说她会去结果她不在的话
And if you say she's gonna be there and she's not,
我会向你的上司明确在所有联邦调查局探员中
I will make it clear to your bosses that I will work
我唯独不与你合作
with any FBI agent except you.
那样你便是
You'll have done all the work to get me,
赔了夫人又折兵
and get nothing for it.
就这样说定了吧?
Do we have an understanding?
你想我们什么时候去接你?
What time do you want us to pick you up?
我会通知你们的
I'll let you know.
我现在得先办点事情
I got something I got to do first.
- Franklin?  - Patrick? 最近如何啊?
- Franklin?  - Patrick? How are you?
好 挺好的 我需要你帮忙
Good. I'm very good. Uh, I need your help.
你跟我说过Danny Otero
You said that Danny Otero was buying some heroin
跟一些越南毒贩购买海洛因
from some Vietnamese dealers.
你不该管Danny Otero的闲事
You should have nothing to do with Danny Otero.
我? 当然不 我都不会接近他
Me? No, of course not. I'm not going anywhere near him.
你知不知道他交易完成了没?
Do you know if he's already made the buy?
没呢 越南人今早刚住进旅馆
No. No, Vietnamese guests only check in this morning.
很好 我需要你帮我查出三件事
Excellent. I need you to find out three things for me.
我什么都查得出
I can find out anything.
第一 交易什么时候进行?
First, when will the deal happen?
第二 他们在哪间房?
Second, what room will they be in?
还有呢?
What else?
呃 对了
Uh, yes.
呃 那些越南人什么时候用餐
Uh, when the Vietnamese will be eating.
没问题 他们从不用正餐 一直待在酒吧
No problem. They never eat. Always in the bar.
很好 Franklin 你棒极了
Excellent, Franklin. You're very good.
非常 非常出色
Very, very good.
多谢
Thank you.
不用找...
No, just...
下午好 抱歉打扰了
Good afternoon. Sorry for the interruption.
呃 我想你们之中有一个会说英语
Uh, I assume one of you speaks English.
我会
I do.
我是Patrick Jane 很高兴认识你
Patrick Jane. Pleased to meet you.
什么意思?
What's this about?
我知道你们是毒贩子 无意冒犯
I know you're drug dealers. I don't judge.
我自己在美国也因杀人被通缉
I'm wanted for homicide myself in the U.S.
我要谈的是我们共同认识的一个人...
What I want to discuss is a mutual acquaintance...
叫Danny Otero
Danny Otero.
他怎么了?
What about him?
我觉得应该提醒你们 他叛变了
Well, I thought I should warn you. He's flipped.
他目前是警方的线人
He's working as an informer to the police.
他和叫Abbott的联邦调查局探员是一伙的
He's teamed up with an FBI agent named Abbott.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know this?
我自己就在另一份协议中
Well, I'm working with Abbott myself
和Abbott是合作关系
on a different deal.
我就是这么知道Otero的名字的
That's how Otero's name came up.
如果你们和Danny Otero做生意
If you have any business with Danny Otero,
奉劝一句良言...
word to the wise...
小心为妙
you might want to be careful.
再见
See ya.
我是Abbott
Abbott.
我15分钟后在1443房间
I'll be in room 1443 in 15 minutes.
就在旅馆里?
Here in the hotel?
我正跟几个朋友
I'm having a little good-bye drink
喝几杯道个别
with some friends.
在门口报上自己的名字
Just identify yourself at the door,
他们就会来叫我了
and they'll come get me.
什么事?
Yes?
联邦调查局的Abbott
Abbott, FBI.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
联邦调查局的Abbott
Abbott, FBI.
Patrick Jane没跟你说我要来吗?
Didn't Patrick Jane tell you I was coming?
等一下
One moment.
- 你把我们出卖给警察了?  - 什么?
- Did you sell us to the police?  - What?
你是不是把我们出卖给警察了?
Did you sell us to the police?
没有 没有...
No, no, no...
联邦调查局的人就在外面
The feds are right outside.
你以为你能逃过一劫?
You think you can get away with this?
- 什么乱七八糟的  - 好吧...
- The hell with this.  - All right...
- 我跟你们说 我没...  - 联邦调查局! 不许动! 不许动!
- I'm telling you, I'm not...  - FBI! Don't move! Don't move!
双手抱头
Put your hands on your head.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
把枪交出来 别磨蹭
Dejo esa. Ahora.
很好
Good job. All right,
现在所有人趴到地上
now everybody get down on the ground.
趴到地上
Down on the ground.
向下
Al suelo.
趴到地上
En el estomago.
嗯?
Huh?
真不错
Ah, that's nice.
非常好
Very nice.
问题只剩下...
The only question is...
Patrick Jane在哪?
where's Patrick Jane?
Abbott 出了什么事?
Abbott, what happened?
是你下的套
You set this up.
是你敲的门
You're the one who knocked on the door.
我的条款
My terms.
我要你读完之后签上名
I need you to read them and sign it.
这些我们可以达成
We can work with this.
很好 那就请签名吧
Excellent. Sign it, please.
好吧
All right.
还有五份复印件
Five more copies.
请把这些也签了吧
Sign those, too, please.
复印件给你
They're for you.
原版留我这
I keep the original.
- 好吧 咱们走  - 等一下
- All right. Let's go.  - Ah, one second.
你个小杂种走路长点眼睛
现在咱们可以出发了
Now we can go.
Jane先生!
Mr. Jane!
德克萨斯州 奥斯丁
Jane啊
Jane.
嘿 Cho
Cho.
哈!
Ha!
你总是给我惊喜
You never cease to amaze me.
从这里开始他由我接管了
I got him from here, guys.
看来你进了联邦调查局?
So you joined the FBI, huh?
没错
Yeah.
五个月前在匡蒂科结束培训
Finished training at Quantico five months ago.
哇 看看你
Wow. Look at you.
祝贺啊
Congratulations.
谢了
Thanks.
好
Yeah.
这边走
It's this way.
好吧
Okay.
你的袜子哪儿去了?
Where are your socks?
呃... 我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
他们是在你后颈植入了芯片吗?
Did they put a chip in your neck?
就我所知没有 问这干什么?
Not that I know of. Why do you ask?
没什么 只是你看起来见到我不是很高兴
Ah, you just don't seem too happy to see me.
见到你我是高兴的
I am happy to see you.
- 我只是希望能换个方式  - 为什么?
- I just wish it was under different circumstances.  - Why is that?
我觉得你和联邦调查局不会合作得很愉快的
I don't think you and the FBI are gonna get along very well.
他们不会真正理解你的做事方式
I don't think they really understand how you operate.
他们了解我之后就不会盯那么紧啦
Ah. They'll loosen up once they get to know me.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
左手边第二扇门
Second door on the left.
嘿
Hey.
你好啊
Hello.
小胡子不错
Nice beard.
谢了
Thank you.
谢谢你那些信
Thank you for the letters.
太想你了
Oh, I missed you.
我也很想你
I missed you, too.
怎么回事? 为什么把我叫来?
What's going on, huh? Why am I here?
- 一会儿就知道了 会很棒的  - 什么?
- You'll see. It's gonna be great.  - What?
相信我
Trust me.
好吧 咱们开工
All right, let's get this started.
Jane... 这些都是
Jane... these are the charges
对你的指控...
pending against you...
凶杀 妨碍执法
homicide, obstruction of justice,
加重恐吓 偷窃等等
aggravated assault, grand theft auto, etcetera.
等待你的是20年的徒刑
You're looking at 20 to life.
但如果你同意在联邦调查局
But all of that can go away if you agree
至少担任五年时间的顾问
to serve as a consultant for the FBI
那些指控都会被撤销
for at least five years.
你由我监管
You will be under my supervision,
处于联邦调查局的假释
on federal parole,
随时由我决定是否撤回
which may be revoked at any time at my discretion.
你要是瞎搞 逃跑 只要是任何令我不悦的事情
You screw up, run away, do anything that I don't like,
你立刻就回监狱里去
and you'll be in the jailhouse.
签字 便一言为定
Sign, and we have a deal.
有意思
Interesting.
嗯
Hmm.
你应该意识到
As you're aware,
你已经同意了某些条款
you have already agreed to some terms.
我没同意
I didn't agree to those.
我签字只是表明已阅
I signed indicating that I read them.
- 有什么区别  - 有的 相信我
- Same difference.  - No, it's not, believe me.
首先 没什么假释 我是自由身
Firstly, no parole. I'm a free man.
其次 Lisbon必须和我一起工作
And secondly, Lisbon has to work with me.
- 什么?  - 你不需要Lisbon的
- Hey, hello?  - Well, you won't need Lisbon.
我已经给你派了一个团队
I've already assembled a team to work with you.
- 这点没的商量  - 我有工作 好吗?
- Oh, that's not negotiable.  - I have a job, okay?
不会因为你突发奇想回来
I'm not gonna drop everything
就让我抛下一切
just because you suddenly decided to come back.
咱... 咱们一会儿再谈 还有一些其它条款...
W... we'll talk. There are some other stipulations...
都是小事情 我肯定咱们能谈拢
Easy stuff. I'm sure we can figure them out.
但你这份里没有一条符合 这...
But none of this applies. This...
你好像没太听明白 Jane
I don't think you're hearing me, Jane.
你现在脚踏美国的领土
You are on U.S. soil now,
我代表联邦政府告诉你
I am the federal government, and I am telling you
那不过是张餐巾
that that is a napkin.
这...
This...
才是协议
is the deal.
要么签...
Take it...
要么走
or leave it.
我走
I'll leave it.
真不幸
Oh, that's too bad.
你犯了个错 但...
You made a mistake, but, hey...
Kim 是你?
Kim?
是Fischer探员
Agent Fischer.
你叫她Kim?
Kim?
是Fischer探员
Agent Fischer.
Fischer探员
Jane先生
Mr. Jane
即将被押往拘留所
will be going to a detention suite.
真不幸啊 我来安排
I'm sorry to hear that. I'll make the arrangements.
我不会捣乱的
Oh, yeah, I'm not fussy.
给我找间看得到外面风景的 我就去
If you have one with a view, I'll take it.
要是没有 也无所谓了
If not, uh, whatever,
只要我能泡茶就好
As long as I can make some tea.
她是谁 还有拘留所算怎么回事?
Who is she, and what is a detention suite?
别担心 Lisbon 一切都在掌控之中
Don't worry, Lisbon. It's all under control.